Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
That's enough !
You've improved a lot, Lord Nol.
You must have noticed from the
last match that Nol lacks something.
I want him to learn that.
His first battle is soon.
Is that why you're taking him out hunting ?
Right. It's only a small group,
so it won't affect the defense of Telezart.
Since the unbeatable Goland
fleet is covering us in orbit...
...I feel as if our Zarvival ground forces are on leave.
Take your entire fleet if you like.
Our division is more than
adequate for a planet like this.
You haven't changed.
Neither have you. I feel like I'm
talking to the late King Goland.
He spared no effort in training his own cadets.
But that's...
...no different than the taboo
of self-esteem among Gatlantians.
Even so, he'll eventually take my position in the fleet and succeed the name of Goland.
His highness Nol is...
Strange. Gatlantis has no
concept of parent or child.
Even so, they talk like human father and son.
Even though we're manufactured,
we're an intelligent humanoid life form.
If so, we might...
Enough, Gailane.
Telezart emits infinite power.
Once I get a hold of Teresa, the source
of that power, our wish will be granted.
Everything else is a mere sideshow.
Does that include the space battleship Yamato,
the ship called by Teresa ?
It was supposed to perish along with a Garmillas fleet by proving that their sense of love is nothing but ego.
But that ship managed to escape
the danger without losing any lives.
It was just a coincidence.
Don't overestimate its potential.
There's no possibility of a coincidence
being part of Teresa's prayer.
The Yamato responded to the prayer,
and it's coming to meet Teresa.
It is fortunate that a copy of a living body
has managed to sneak aboard the Yamato.
However, I must doubt whether it's a coincidence or not.
I see fear in you.
Is it of Teresa or...?
Doctor, it's ready.
It's no wonder why you have a medical license.
It's only from expedited training
during war-time though...
What is it ?
Oh, it's nothing. You're fine.
No abnormalities ?
Sorry.
Mori is way too concerned.
Perhaps I should prescribe some vitamin tablets.
I don't need any. Excuse me.
What's the holdup this time ?
You were determined to take the Yamato out, despite the risk of becoming rebels.
We've completed a third of our trip.
If we maintain this course for Telezart...
....there will be the White Comet right ahead of us.
Kodai, did the guy who manipulated the professor say that the White Comet was their homeland ?
No, not clearly.
That's pretty vague.
The message from Telezart is unclear, too. There was no follow-up after the first one.
Either way, we can't ignore the risk of the
Yamato facing the main forces of our enemy.
If we need to return to Earth to reorganize our forces, now is the time to withdraw.
To the Yamato crew, it looks like you're quite far away.
I'm going to deliver the decision made by Earth HQ.
We want you to maintain your current course,
and obtain as much intel as possible on the White Comet.
Discovery and arrival at
Telezart were our objectives, but...
...if the White Comet is a
major outpost of Gatlantis...
..."get closer for recon ?"
I'm not saying how close.
I'll leave that decision up to the Yamato's crew.
Kodai...
Don't worry.
The Yamato's objectives haven't changed.
We'll keep going as planned.
About the Acting Captain...
He seems to be exhausted,
both mentally and physically.
He's been tense ever since he
received the message from Teresa.
The concern over the wave motion gun, and the shock and pressure of making contact with Gatlantis...
It's normal to act abnormally ?
He acts tough, but he's naive inside.
Excuse me.
Don't worry.
Kodai will pull through this journey.
You chose him.
Who else could trust him better ?
Right...
That's true.
We're the only ground forces here.
There are no replacements.
We must use our skills to make up
for inadequate protection and firepower.
What's that ?
Commander...
It looks like some kind of living organism,
but they might pose a risk without further analysis...
...so make sure no one lets
them out of the canisters
It looks beautiful, but I can't let it fly freely, huh ?
Shino, Yamato is a warship.
Right.
No, I heard Mr. Sanada wanted some samples.
I heard it was Chief Intelligence Officer Niimi.
Hey, Ms. Niimi is...
Oh, she's on Earth now.
Where did that rumor come from ?
Oh, Acting Captain.
Nanbu...
They're fireflies.
There used to be some on Earth in the past.
They look beautiful. Here.
So beautiful...
What's all the commotion about ?
Is that...
I feel a sense of nostalgia.
A taste of grandma's rice cake...
Tsubasa, Makoto...
Akio...?
What are you staring at ?
Lieutentant Keyman...
This isn't so good...
About what ?
The fireflies.
Fireflies ?
You aren't affected ?
No.
How about you, Doctor ?
I prefer sake.
So beautiful...
Wow...
Hey, is this okay ?
I thought those weren't supposed
to be released from the canisters.
Who's that ?
He looks like a ghost.
How pathetic.
Captain Okita, what should I...
Kodai, you're such a lucky guy.
Hey, Commander.
Ouch...
Commander.
On both the 11th planet and
Stravase, you were saved by luck.
You haven't made a tough decision yet.
Probably not.
What about the future ?
Are you going to put the ship in danger
because of your humanitarian views ?
Then hurry back to Earth,
and let us get off the Yamato !
I want to be on a ship where I can fight !
There's no need for a ship of cowards.
Take back what you said.
There you are.
Operations Chief Mori, we have a problem.
Our commander and Acting Captain Kodai are...
Kodai...?
I don't mean to be disrespectful
to the spirits of the war dead.
But you don't know how hard it is to keep waiting.
I was saved by Hijikata during the war.
I'll owe him forever.
But many didn't make it...
...while waiting for help that never came, while
crawling in the mud that smelled of dead bodies...
You should know that you can still sense the
smell of dead bodies in the vacuum of space !
All the survivors carry the burden of letting them die.
Letting them die...
We must avenge the dead.
But what the hell are you doing ?!
Hey, he's the Acting Captain.
You're a soldier, aren't you ?
Say what ?
Wait.
Forget about titles.
I don't care what you
say about me, but the Yamato...
...is Okita's ship !
Apologize !
Interesting.
Hey, are you guys serious ?
What's the problem ? Let them do it.
Right.
We have to settle this.
Don't be ridiculous.
This won't end with a few scratches.
Commander, you're facing an amateur.
Both of you, stop ! Just stop !
Engine problem.
The wave motion reactor is unstable.
Energy must be flowing back into the conductor pipe.
That's it.
That frequency range.
It's a success. If we emit this wave,
the hypnosis will be cured.
What ? What happened ?
Commander Saito.
It's an emergency.
You're in charge here.
You can count on me.
Are they going to devour the system ?
Mr. Sanada !
Kodai, so you're safe.
Chief Engineer, bypass the wave motion
coil to send energy to the engine.
Are you going to burn the fireflies ?
That's too risky !
It'll be too late if we lose pressure because of erosion to the conductive pipe. Hurry.
If we fail, the Yamato might blow up.
We have to do it.
Chief Engineer...
Everyone, hold your breath.
Are they dead ?
Chief Engineer, what's the situation ?
Current engine output is 50%.
Everything is normal.
So my bug killer worked, huh ?
Dr. Sado...?
Bug killer ?
It's actually for a virus, instead of a bug.
I didn't know if it'd work, but I had it just in case.
I didn't notice.
Don't blame yourself.
You still stopped their effect on brainwaves.
Well, that was Keyman's...
Is your device still intact ?
I thought I'd be able to see you if I waited in here.
Yes, this warmth.
What's on your mind ?
I won't say anything.
Once again, a cosmo wave from Telezart...
Mr. Sanada, is that...
There's nothing on radar.
Space is warped, and energy is rising.
A dimensional projection ? If so, from where ?
Evasive maneuvers !
Wait !
Kodai...
Neither time nor space is an issue, but there are things you can't see until you get closer.
You have all come this far,
even without any concrete evidence.
This time, we'll show you the proof.
Mr. Okita, I'm no good.
I can't manage the crew as a leader.
I couldn't keep your promise with Starsia.
What should I do now ?
How should I lead the Yamato ?
Kodai, you're doing well.
Don't you think you've done well so far ?
Captain.
Your heart knows which direction to go.
Wait, Captain.
Mr. Okita...
Follow your heart.
Is that what he meant by showing us proof ?
Teresa...
Beautiful...
I understand.
Would you accept then ?
I'm a loser.
But I'll tag along.
I've seen it after all.
I saw it.
Yeah.
It was my late sister.
You're no longer our guest.
Welcome to the Yamato.
How about you ?
Who was in your vision ?
I...
I don't know what's going on,
but we were called, too, right ?
Right. Welcome aboard.
Thanks.
We have the option of turning back.
HQ's order was to make the decision ourselves.
Let's move forward.
There's something out there, something seeking help.
It can only pray, despite a tough situation.
Even so, it won't stop praying.
We humans won't stop either.
Set the base course to Telezart.
We'll initiate a warp in two hours.
They're your kids. I knew it.
Episode 10
Deceptive Space Fireflies Bring Danger
Kienai de aoi tsuki yo
Blue moon, please don't fade away
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Analyzer:
Kato Saburo:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Yamamoto Akira:
Tsurumi Jiro:
Kouda Minoru:
Hayashi Shigeru:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Cho
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Hirata Daisuke
Tanaka Rie
Komoto Jiro
Fujinuma Kento
Matsumoto Shinobu
Terashidasu kimi hitohira
It lights up my love just enough
Saito Hajime:
Shiori Nagakura:
Amagi Toshiro:
Kurata Masaru:
Okita Juzo:
Hijikata Ryu:
Kodai Mamoru
Toudo Heikuro:
Desler:
Keyman:
Zorder:
Sabera:
Gailane:
Zarvival:
Goland:
Nol:
Genitz:
Lazera:
Touchi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Saito Jiro
Yoshikai Kiyoto
Sugao Takayuki
Ishizuka Unsho
Miyamoto Mitsuru
Kojima Toshihiko
Yamadera Koichi
Kamiya Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Kaida Yuko
Shibata Hidekatsu
Yara Yusaku
Yamaji Kazuhiro
Hikami Takahiro
Umezu Hideyuki
Harasawa Kouki
Nani hitotsu kawaranai
Everything was routine
Monotone iro no hibi
Monotone days for so long
Unmei ga tsurete kita
Fate brought you to me
Kimi no me ni koi wo shita
I fell in love with your eyes
Chikaku ni kanjitai yo
I want to feel you close
Atatakai te ni furete
Touching your warm hands
Aa sugu ni kotoba ni dekitara
Wishing I could put this into words right away
Konnani ai shiteru
I love you so much
Kakurenai de koigokoro yo
Loving feelings, please don't hide
Kimi dake terashiteru yo
It sheds light only on you
Konya nara sou ieru
I can say that because tonight is different
He's going to have his own fleet ?
Yes, by direct order of the Emperor.
Why ? He was just some half dead
loser that was drifting in space.
We, Gatlantis, have no equivalent word for
"demoted general's position" or "second chance."
It is unusual for us to entrust
a fleet to someone like you.
You had better thank His Majesty.
Sabera...
...pay respect to the king of a nation.
I want you to show us something...
...and it's called...
...tenacity.
I've arranged the gift you desire most.
How is it, Fuhrer Desler ?
Much appreciated.
Preview
Are we surrounded ?
All ahead full ! Pull away !
We're completely surrounded !
The size of the fleet is ridiculously huge !
Open all suction valves !
At this rate, the Yamato will...
Watch me carefully.
I am a man who never forgets humiliation.
Episode 11
Challenge from Desler !